번역: 콘트롤러 (=esamdr)
도와주세요
누구 있어요?
다쳤어요
누구 계세요?
여기요
피 나요
도와주세요
총 치워요
당신 먼저 치워요
치워요!
알겠어요
당신 차례에요
다른 손 꺼내봐요
이 손 치우면, 심장 떨어질까 겁나요
다른 손 봐야겠어요
그 손에 뭐있어요?
없어요
총 좀 치워요
손에 뭐 있냐구요
예전의 내가 그립다
안녕
평범 그자체 고딩이었는데
안녕! 잘지내니
안녕!
곤배~
고마워. 곤배~
일이 이렇게 될줄은 정말..
살인자 캐시..
걔도 여기 있어야 되는데
누구?
왜 괜찮은 애는 늘 그렇게 못마땅해야 돼?
말할게 뭐 있어야지
난 걔 몰라, 걔도 나 모르고
넌 암놈, 걔는 숫놈
넌 숫이랑 같이..
됏어
오 이런
알겠어 리즈
뭐가?
월욜날 너 보러 갈께
으.
집에 가야돼
개구멍 찾기!
알았어
살랑해
잘가
집에 가서 문자해
알았어
안녕-
안녕
폰 케이스 이쁘다
왜? 핑크색 비호감이야?
아니, 아냐. 완전 좋아해
장난이야
어. 사실 이거 여동생 핸폰이야
파자마 파티 데려다 주러 갔는데, 모르고 내껄 가져갔어
내껀 훨씬 좋지
스파이더맨 이거든
내껀 도트..
아하, 여동이네
여보세요
어... 그래, 여깄어
아니, 니 문자 안받았어
"폰 케이스 이쁘다."?
어쩔
노래 불러줭
노래?
그래, 눈감아
이게 말이 돼?
아니
통금시간, 기말고사
어이, 벤
하지마
축구연습
설리번, 뭐하니 지금?
공을 아주 갖다 바치지 그래
자, 준비
썰, 여기 이거 좀 봐, 별 희안한..
봐봐
암것두 안보이는데
야, 알츌러
너 진짜.. 나가
아뇨, 그게.. 정말 이상한 일이...
됏다! 나가. /빠이빠이/
알고보면,
세상의 종말을 아무리 예상한다 해도
결국 그 예상을 벗어난다
뭐, 연예급 누가 죽기라도 한거야?
세상에, 여기랑 가깝잖아
보러 갈래
샘
안돼, 샘, 잠깐만..
샘, 기다려
저 우주 쇠떵이들이 뭘 원하는지는 아무도 모른다
처음 10일동안은 그랬다
이름도 생겼는데
우린 저들을 "타귀"라고 부른다
윌슨네도 떠나네?
여긴 도저히 불안해서 안되겠대
그래,
이게 다 온거니?
그래, 그럼
칠판에 써 있는 방정식을 보자
누가 X함수 풀어보겠니?
누가할까
아무도없니
잠깐 정전인거 같구나
핸드폰 안돼
뭔 일이야
저기야
맙소사, 무슨 일이..
뒤로가, 물러서
타귀들이 EMP 파동으로 우릴 공격하고 있다
모든 전기시설이 파괴됐다
엔진 무작동
전기 무작동
수돗물도 끊겼다
일상적인 모든게.. 멈췄다
그때가 벤 패리쉬를 본 마지막이였다
지금쯤은 죽었겠지.
그때 그자리에 있던 아이들도..
샘, 여기, 다른 통도 줘, 땡큐
그때가 제1침공이였다
그때만 해도 그걸로 끝인줄 알았다
제2침공이 곧 이어졌다
샘, 이리와, 지진이야!
누나!
조심해!!
어서!
뛰어!뛰어! 괜찮아
누나!
괜찮아,..
머리 숙이고 있어
저건 무슨 소리야?
샘, 뛰어!
올라가!
누나!
누나 빨리와!
이리와, 누나 꽉 잡아
오하이오에서는 호수 하나가 문제였지만
바다 였다면..
생각만 해도..
모든 해변 도시들
모든 섬들이
다 사라졌다
지구상엔 3천억 종의 새들이 있지만
사람들은 75개 종 정도만 안다
엄마는 변종 플루가 지구상에서 가장 위험한
바이러스라고 말해주셨다
제3침공은 수위가 낮아졌지만
대응은 엄두도 못냈다
새들은 우리를 떠나 저 멀리로 날아갔다
A선에 맞춰 서세요
그래야 확인됩니다
A선과 B선을 구분하세요
저쪽으로 쭉 가세요
난 멀쩡하다고!
안전구역으로 들어가게 해줘!
야, 리즈!
어,
니네 엄마가 너 여깄대
캐시! 캐시
엄마?
너 지금 뭐...
쟤 감염됫어
알아, 안 만졌어
뭘 알아, 넌 여기 있음 안돼
미안해 엄마.
우리딸, 얼른 집에 가, 동생 챙기고 있어.
아니, 나도 돕고 싶어 엄마
니맘알아, 얘 좀 내보내주실래요?
돕고싶어
엄마
아냐, 괜찮아. 넌 가야돼
나가야 돼요, 가요
바이러스에 면역인 사람들은 소수였다
걸린 사람들, 나아진 사람들도 있었지만
대다수는........
똥깡
그 신발은 아닌거 같다
언제까지 이러고 있어야 돼?
뭘 원하는거야
더 중요한 질문은, "그들한테 뭐가 필요한가?"겠지
지금까진 뭔가 사리고 있어
불필요하게 뭘 해치지도 않아
해치다니?
지구
내 생각엔 그게 이유인거 같다, 캐시.
그들한테 지구가 필요해
우린 아니네
그래, 우린 아냐
오래걷기 할 수 있니, 새미?
응
그래
아빠, 대피소까지 많이 멀어?
좀 가야지, 해지기 전까진 도착해야돼
아빠, 여기봐, 이거그거야?
응, 똥깡, 그런거같다
어서들 와요
고맙습니다
허취필드 에요
안내 해 드릴께요
저쪽이 화장실
텃밭은 저쪽 밖에 있어요
마실 물 있어요?
네. 그게 어디에요, 그쳐?
사람들이 얼마나 있나요?
세어보진 않았는데..
300여명 쯤..
식당은 여기구요
집밥같은 밥 먹은게 언제에요?
워우, 아빠
45구경 권총이야
이렇게, 알겠지?
여길 누르면 탄창이 빠져
이러면, 장전된거야
알겟니? 안전잠금 걸고
안전잠금 풀고
잘들어
이걸 항상 지니고 있어, 하지만
누구한테도 말하지는 마
반드시 생사의 순간에만 이걸 써
알겠니
여긴 안전하다고 생각했는데
이쁜딸, 어디에도 안전은 없어
뭐지?
샘, 이리와
뭐야?
모르겠어, 가자
아빠 보여?
아빠 저기!
캐시?
아빠
응
무슨 일이야?
진정하세요 다들
차는 다 고장인거 아니였어?
여려분, 전 미육군 소속 보쉬 대령입니다.
저희 부대는 공군기지에서 나왔습니다
구조하러 온거죠
드디어!
자, 저희와 함께 가시죠
앗싸!
미국 멋난다!!
갈 준비 빨리 끝내야 돼 알겠니?
누나랑 있어 샘
가자
버스 타세요
성인들은
파악을 위해 이쪽으로 오세요
아이들은 바로 버스에 타면 됩니다
바로 따라갈께, 별일 없을거야
성인들은 이쪽으로 모여주세요
여기가면 전기도 있겠지? 트럭도 다니는데
글쎄다, 왜? 핸폰 아직 있어?
그럼이징
충전기도 있고?
그럼그럼이징
잠깐요 잠깐요.
네?
저희 절차는 애들만 일단 버스탑니다.
그게 무슨 절차에요, 전 얘들 보호자에요
네
그럼 같이 기다리다,
다른 버스 같이 탈께요
제군
내가 맡지
네, 써
고맙네
음, 다같이 모여 있겠다 하시면, 좋습니다.
근데 제가 선생님 입장이라면, 전 애들 먼저 버스에 태울겁니다
왜죠?
이곳에 공격이 곧 있을 거라는 정보가 있습니다.
최대한 많은 인원을 빠르게 대피시킬 겁니다만,
수송 차량은 한계가 있고,
일단 갔다와야죠
아이들 먼저 태우고, 다시 올겁니다
공군기지는 얼마나 안전한가요?
현재로선 가장 안전한 곳입니다
버스는 금방 돌아오구요?
아빠, 안돼요
애들 내려주고, 바로 옵니다
말씀드렸듯이, 선택하시면 됩니다
군복입은 사람이 말했다고 해서
반드시 따를 이유는 없잖아
좋아, 너네 먼저 가야겠다
아빠도 금방 갈께
떨어지기 싫어요
이따 거기서 저녁먹자, 금방 다시 볼꺼야
싫어요 아빠
캐시
군인들이야, 응? 별일 없을 거야
아빠 없음 무서워
괜찮아. 캐시
사랑한다
동생 잘 챙기고 있어, 알겠지? 이리와
누나 말 잘 들어야 한다. 알겠지?
네
누나가 보호자야
아빠.
얼른 타
금방 따라갈께
뒤로 가자 샘
응
가방 줘봐
곰돌이!
응?
곰돌이 잊어버렸어
누나
샘, 샘. 왜그래?
곰돌이, 곰돌이 찾아야 돼
샘, 그만 앉아봐
왜그래?응?
안돼, 꼭 있어야 돼
누나!
알았어, 내가 가져올게, 응?
넌 여기 있어
빨리 갔다 올께
진짜?
응, 완전 빨리, 진짜로
샘돌아 어딨니
곰탱 곰탱 곰탱 곰탱
오, 이런, 샘!
저기요, 잠깐만요!
멈춰요!
샘!
누나! 멈춰요.
새ㅁ, 안돼, 샘, 기다려
샘!
누나, 빨리!
누나!
샘!
안돼!
누나, 이이..잉..
아..ㄴ...돼..
안..ㄷㅙ...
씌...ㅍ
자, 주목해 주세요
차분하게, 여길 보세요
제4침공이 시작 되었습니다
타귀들이 상륙했습니다.
우릴 쫓아 올겁니다
정보에 따르면, 타귀들은 인간 몸속으로 들어가
숙주로 삼고 그들을 조종한다고 합니다
그럼, 우리랑 구분이 안되나요?
네 맞습니다
어디 있는대요?
어디든 가능합니다
저희가 알기론, 저들이 조종하는 저격수들이 숲속에 있다가
사람들을 쏜다고 하던데요
저희도 이곳 어딘가에 그런 저격수들이
있을 거라 관측하고 있습니다
뭐, 그럼.. 여기 그놈들이 있다는 거에요?
자, 아직 불확실한 게 많습니다
아이들의 경우는 감지, 식별이 가능한데
불행히도, 성인들의 경우는
감지 시스템상 어려움이 있습니다
우리 애들은 어째요?
맞아요, 애들 어쩔거에요?
네,네, 가족끼리 떨어진다는게 힘든거 압니다
어쩔수없이, 여기 계신 여러분의 경우는
식별 테스트를 더 받아야 되는
그런 상황입니다
여러분.!
이해해 주셔야 됩니다. 불가피한 절차로,
식별은 반드시 해야 됩니다
확실한 식별이 되어야만
여러분 자신도 안전하고
그래야 가족들도 다시 만날 수 있고,
좆까! 씨ㅂ!
난 그것도 아니고, 아무데도 안갈꺼야
그렇다고 얘기 한 사람 없어요
어쩔수없는 상황입니다
다들 진정해주세요
부탁드립니다. 진정하세요
난 나갈거야, 비켜요, 비켜요
잠시만요
당장 물러서
꼼짝마
총 내리세요
비켜
총 내리세요!
나 막지 마
제발 진정 좀 하세요
나갈꺼야!
총 내려 당장!
우리 애들 보고싶다고!!
내려!!!
저리 비켜!
안돼! 그만!!
숙여!
도망쳐!
아ㄴ..돼, 아ㄴ..돼, 안돼
흐ㄱ,ㅅ....아.빠..
.....아ㅃ..ㅏ....
어..떻게...
죄..송..해요.
아빠...
아빠 없이 어떻게..
악!!
SOLDIER: Security teams, clear zones three and four.
Security teams, clear zones three and four.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Support team members, meet arrivals on the tarmac.
? ?
Stand in the red circle. Wait for your number to be called.
MAN: (OVER SPEAKERS) Number 127.
295.
2-9-5.
Here.
Number 7-3, 73.
Number 74.
Number 130.
194.
1-3-0.
1-9-4.
SERGEANT REZNIK: What's your name?
Ben Parish.
They called me "Zombie"in quarantine.
Any family not known to be dead?
No.
Sister died in the quakes.
Mom and Dad killed by the virus.
But it didn't kill you, did it?
Not quite.
That where the nickname came from?
You fought it off.
Yeah, lucky me.
Is this your sister's?
Yeah.
Well, lucky you.
You get to help avenge her death.
This puts out a signal that we can track.
You kids are the most important thing right now.
We need every one of you to help us fight the Others.
This isn't summer camp, Zombie. You're a soldier now.
So we don't wanna lose you. Stand up.
Turn around.
Take a deep breath.
(INHALES)
You all right?
How are we supposedto fight the Others
if we don't evenknow what they are?
Actually, we do.
You wanna see one?
Don't worry. He won't be able to see us.
I know. It's impossible to tell.
Look through here.
Look.
(EKG BEEPING)
That's its true form.
The Others infest real humans like some sort of parasite.
Take over their minds, their bodies.
Drugs, radiation,surgery, nothing works.
The only way to kill 'em is to kill the host.
He's already dead.
You just need to destroy the thing inside him.
The thing that did this.
Push the button.
Look again!
Look!
If you're gonnabe on my squad,
I need to knowthat you will dowhatever it takes to...
(SCREECHING)
(EKG FLATLINING)
Welcome to the fight.
CASSIE: Here's how you kill off a species.
First, you take out the easy ones, the weak, the exposed.
Kill them as efficiently as possible.
That was the first three Waves.
But even if you bug bomb a house,
there's always a few cockroaches left.
Now, we are like those cockroaches.
And the Others are picking us off.
One by one.
? ?
And because the Others look like us,
we can't trust anyone.
? ?
(RUSTLING)
(GASPS)
? ?
(HOOTING)
Eighty miles to Wright-Patterson.
I'm coming, Sammy.
I promise.
? ?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(PANTING)
? ?
CASSIE: How do you rid the world of humans?
MAN: Help me.
(GUN SHOTS)
First, you rid the humans of their humanity.
(SNIFFS)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
Shit.
(GUN SHOTS)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
Shi... Shi...
God!
Sam.
All right. All right.
(CONTINUES PANTING)
(STRAINING)
(YELLS)
God!
I'm sorry, Sam.
COLONEL VOSCH: When I was a child, I spoke as a child.
I thought and I reasoned as a child.
But when I became a man,
I put away childish things.
Those words nevermeant more to methan they do right now,
looking at all of you.
Our hope. Our future.
The best and brightest vision of who we are and what we're fighting for.
Our intelligencetells us the Others are
readying themselvesfor a final attack.
(SIGHS) The 5th Wave.
What form it will take,we do not know.
If they are successful,
there will be no more Waves.
No more conflicts.
Humanity as we know it will be wiped from the face of the Earth.
Now.
I'm gonna tell you some things I know.
This is our world.
It is our home.
They will not overrun it.
They will not possess it.
(GUN SHOTS)
So with whatever time we have left,
you will learn to think, speak,
move and fight like the soldiers you are.
FEMALE RECRUIT 1: Look out! A raid!
FEMALE RECRUIT 2: Go!
Fire!
Let the weight of our loss fuel you.
Let the weight of our dead embolden you.
FEMALE RECRUIT 3: Your right! On your right!
Let the weight of our hope drive you to victory.
Can you do that?
All right. Hold!
Soldiers! Can you do that?
ALL: (IN UNISON)Sir, yes, sir!
? ?
Zombie!
(CLIP CLATTERS)
Get down!
It's a booby trap!
Can you do that?
ALL: (IN UNISON)Sir, yes, sir!
Good.
(CREAKING)
(GASPS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
? ?
(DOOR CLOSES)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Come on.
Where's my gun? Where's my gun?
Where is it?
(GROANS)
I know you're awake.
Cassie?
How the hell do you know my name?
Your driver's license.
I'm Evan.
Evan Walker.
Where am I?
You were bleeding on the highway.
I brought you back here to my house.
Where's my gun?
All right, when you found me on
the highway, I had my gun. Where is it?
I didn't see any gun.
What did you do?
Your leg, Cassie.
Don't touch me! Don't touch me! Don't...
Your leg.
Jesus.
(GROANS)
Oh, God.
Put your leg over here.
This is gonna hurt.
All right. Just do it. Just do it.
Oh, God.
EVAN: Okay.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Oh, God. (GROANS)
How long have I been here?
About a week.
Oh, God.
How far is Wright-Patterson from here?
The military base?
Uh, about 60 miles.
Why?
(YELLS) Jesus!
(WIND CHIME TINKLING)
Hey. It's okay.
You're safe here.
No.
All right, we're not safe anywhere anymore.
Why did you wanna know how close Wright-Patterson was?
Uh...
It's my brother.
The Army took him there, so I...
I need to get him back.
What?
You should eat.
(LIQUID POURING)
You gotta getyour strength back.
Why'd you bring me here?
What do you want?
My family.
I couldn't save them,
but I could save you.
? ?
The way everything's happened, I guess it just makes me feel more...
Human.
And you need help with that?
Feeling human?
Don't you?
? ?
Maybe. (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
You're cheating.
I'm not cheating.
Don't you tell him my card.
You hear me, Oompa?
Hey, I've been getting pretty lucky,
and this isn't my first time playing.
By the way, I heard the new guy coming in
got kicked out of their last squad.
For what?
Disciplinary issues.
That true, boss?
That's what they say.
What's his name?
SERGEANT REZNIK: The name's Ringer.
And he is a she.
Bunk's over there.
GIRL 1: Did you ever do karate before?
GIRL 2: No.
GIRL 1:Sure looks like you did.
You Zombie?
Yeah.
I was the leader of my last squad.
No doubt.
So the guy I replace went Section 8. Why?
Does it matter?
I heard it's 'cause this squad's so bad
he was afraid you'd get him killed when the 5th Wave hits.
ZOMBIE: Uh-huh. It's your squad, too, now.
Hey!
Keep staring at my ass
and I'll rip your throats out.
Let's be clear.
I'm not taking orders from you.
I'm not gonna die with you geniuses.
Good to know.
If anyone in thisbarrack touches me,I'll kill them.
Got it?
Anything else?
I like to play chess. Do you play?
No, actually.
But if you wanna play some strip poker later on...
Ha!
Oh, shit!
And no demeaning, sexist remarks.
She's cool.
(INDISTINCT THUDDING)
? ?
(FLOORBOARD CREAKS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(CLATTERING)
Quiet.
? ?
You had my gun the whole time! Why'd you lie?
I was afraidyou'd shoot me.
For all I knew, you were an Other.
Yeah, well...
Was he one? Out there?
Yeah.
The woods are full of 'em.
They're using those drones to hunt down survivors.
He looked so human that...
Oh, God. I gotta get Sam.
Cassie.
Rallying points, places like Wright-Patterson,
they're obvious targets.
? ?
You think that Sammy's already dead?
I'm sorry, Cassie.
You're wrong, Evan.
All right? He's alive.
He's alive, and I'm gonna go get him.
Cassie.
I'm going with you.
You're not gonna make it very far on your own.
You know what? Screw you, Evan.
Okay? I don't need you. I don't need anyone.
Cassie, come on.
If you go, I'll just follow you.
Actually, no.
If I need someone to carve a cane for me...
You can't stop me. How are you gonna stop me?
I don't know. Maybe I'll shoot you!
What, like you shot that guy with the crucifix?
What, you read my journal?
I didn't think you were gonna live.
Don't touch me!
I'm sorry.
I'll get you there.
I can't promise what you'll find, but I will get you there.
We leave in the morning.
RINGER: This is a waste of time.
Go ahead and try it again.
Those kids are gonna bedead before theirboots hit the ground.
Especially with you as squad leader.
You don't know anything about me.
Let me guess.
You did good in school, had a bunch of friends.
You probably played football.
You might have even been team captain.
Life was easy.
And then, all of a sudden, it wasn't.
No more games to win.
No one to get weak-kneed at that pretty smile.
You weren't ready for the end of the world.
And you were?
I know how to survive.
And I was doing fine out there on my own.
Till they forced me onto their stupid school bus.
They were rescuing us.
We didn't get rescued, dumbass. We got drafted.
Good, good.
Try it again.
? ?
(GRUNTING)
How about this?
I take you down,
you teach us how to shoot.
And when you don't?
I stop asking.
Deal.
Cute necklace. Girlfriend or sister?
Sister. (GROANS)
You're too sentimental.
(GRUNTS)
? ?
Can you teach me thatthing where you tookthe gun out of my hand?
Let's just leave any potential disarming to me,
all right?
No.
No, I need to be ready.
Cassie, it's okay.
You don't have to be tough all the time.
Don't do that.
I'm not tough, okay?
I promised Sam that I would be there for him no matter what.
I made that promise to him.
Okay.
Give me your gun.
Get up.
Point it at my chest.
Okay. Grab the barrel of the gun with your left,
and with your right, snap my hand away.
You got it?
Hey, you're not gonna hurt me. All right.
Like that, but stronger.
Good.
Now at the end,you'll grab my wristand pull it toward you.
Like that?
Yeah.
Good job.
Well, thanks.
? ?
Can I have...
RINGER: Okay. Don't be so scared of your weapon.
You gotta think that the gun is a part of you.
Not the gun firing, you firing.
Try it again.
(GUN SHOTS)
Well, that wasn't terrible.
Zombie, the Colonel wants to see you, now.
COLONEL VOSCH: Could be. Seems like a good target.
Be right back.
Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
Simultaneous attacks on the last of our metropolitan areas.
A full-on invasion. This is it.
The 5th Wave.
It's started?
Yeah.
Here, I want to show you something.
These employ the same technology
as the detector viewer from medical.
We've improved it. Made it mobile.
The idea is to allow our soldiers in the field
to instantly differentiate between friend and foe.
You look atthe enemy through thisand it lights 'em up green.
We can see them before they know they've been seen.
We take back the advantage.
The only thing left to do now is
test the opticsin live conditions.
Which is why tomorrow at 2100,
I'm sending four squadsinto battle equippedwith these helmets.
Your squad will be among those four.
Yes, sir.
Make me proud, son.
Bring that squad back in one piece.
Yes, sir.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Evan?
? ?
존아침
침Who've we got here?
어...
얜 엘리자베스야.
제일 친한 친구야
웃길거 같다
응. 맞아. 좀...
웃긴 구석이 많았지
그리고 이 남자는
앤 아무도 아냐
벤 패리쉬네
오. 이런
와우
내 일기장 읽었지 참
진짜 챙피하다
가족들이야?
응
얘는 샘이겠네
꼭 한번 보고싶다
가야될거 같아
그래
이쪽이야
나침반도 없이 어떻게 알아?
나침반 있어?
아니...
그치만 손바닥 침 치기는 할 수 있어
걸스카우트 냄새나
그럼 뭘바래?
치어리더?
딩동댕. 난 아무말 안했어
난 야생은 별 소질 없어
벌레도 많고
농촌에서 살잖아
농촌태생일 뿐이야
켄트에서 학교 다녔어
기계공학 전공
촌뜨기라고 생각했지?
딩동댕. 난 아무말 안했어
좀비형. 정말 우리를 전쟁터로 보낼까?
응
무서워
괜찮을꺼야
이제 자는거야 알겠지?
옛날엔 이름이 뭐였어?
벤
넌?
샘
근데 누나는 나를 샘스라고 불렀어
잠이 안올때면
누나가 자장가 불러줬어
돌덩이 마냥 가라앚는 뼈들 #
우리 모두가 싸워온 것들 #
우리가 태어나고 자란 곳#
우리의 모든 것이 그곳에#
좀 닥쳐줄래?
세상은 아름답고~#
그럼그럼~아름답지~
아름다운 세상에 산다ㄴㅔ~
내가 도와줄께
응 그래
좋아졌네
응
새로 묶어줄께
그래
가위 있어?
응
여기
뭘로 덮어야 될 것 같....
에반
고마워
팀-53?
투입준비 전원 완료했습니다
좋아
탑승해라
너겟은 어딨어?
식중독 걸렸어
좀비형
나 좀 풀어줘
작전내용 숙지했나?
호르넷 소굴에 잠입. 적군 식별 후 사살입니다
명심해라, 적군 피아식별은 녹색으로 보일꺼다
작전 완료되면 퇴각 신호 보내라
집에 간다
이런 썅. 진짜 녹색보이네. 전방 적군 둘 관측.
사정권. 이 개노무 쉐이들..
오줌쌋어. 오줌나와
안으로 들어가!
반격 개시!
3시 적군 출현!
9시도 적군 출현!
구석으로 가!
꼬우! 뛰어!뛰어!
빨리 가!
가! 서둘러!
꼬우!
꼬!꼬!꼬!
적군 사격!
숙여!
버스 안으로 숨자
가!
티컵은 어딨어?
티컵 어딨어? 티컵이 없어.
여깄어!
장난치지마! 존나 쫄려 그런거!
움파가 맞았어
숙여! 숙여!!!
숙여!
숨을 안쉬어!
죽지마 임마.
죽지마 제발 죽지마
움파..견뎌..움파
오래 못 버텨요. 다시 올겁니다.
저쪽 골목길. 저기서 반격 준비하자
안돼 너무 멀어
노출 타임이 길게되면
따닥으로 한명씩 당할거야
주의를 돌려야돼
오케이
오키. 뭐가 오키야?
내가 따돌릴께
달리기 알려줄때 말했지 죽도록 뛰라고
엄호해!
뭣?
잘 들어!
저쪽 골목까지 내 뒤로 바짝 따라붙어
뒤쪽으로 나가요? 미치신거 아니에요?
잘들어. 티컵. 그냥 날 믿고 따라와. 응?
겁나 뛸거야. 뒤돌아 보지마
움파는 어쩌구요?
이미 죽었어. 두고 가야돼
미안해 정말 미안해
좀비, 지금이야 뛰어
뛸 준비!
출발! 고우고우고우!!
빨리 움직여!! 고우고우!!
계단 확인해
네
이상무!
우리 아직 살아있는거에요?
그런거 같다
조심해!
쏘지마! 나야
완젼 깜놀이다 링어
일부러 깜놀시킨게 아니라면
겁나 반갑긴 하다
그럼 이제 어떻하지?
뭔가 말이 안돼
하늘이고 땅이고 다 쪼개고 다니는 애들이
고작 애들 부대한테 저 난리라고?
보쉬가 말하지 않은게 분명 있어
그래 난 여기서 종치고 싶지 않아
링어, 뭐하는 거야 너
난 빠질래
내 방식대로 하는게 낫겠어
각자에게 최선이 뭔지 안다면, 나랑 똑같이 할꺼야
이런 썅. 뭐야 저건?
좀비 저거 보여?
쟤 녹색이야
뭐야 왜 이래 다들?
총 내려
너도 그거야! 외계인이라고
뭔 개소리야. 난 니네 살려준 사람이야
쟤가 그게 맞다면, 당장 죽여야 돼
파운케익, 진정해, 응?
죽여야돼
보여!
그녀 속에 뭐가 있는지 보여
내 속엔 아무것도 없어
닥쳐!
좀비, 어떻게해? 그냥 쏴버려?
니가 결정해라. 좀비
좀비, 뭐해?
무슨 일이야 응?
이런 세상에. 뭐가 어떻게 되는..
뭐야 이거
헤이. 총내려. 총내려봐
진정하고, 쏘지마. 그녀는 적이 아니야. 나도 그렇고
그래 나도 발광녹색이지?. 응?
그래
그래.그래.잘들어봐
날 알잖아
이봐 덤보, 내가 누군지 알잖아
총내려놔
빨리 내려놔. 난 적이 아니야
우리한테 총질하는 바깥에 있는 놈들도
적이라고 생각되지 않아
레즈닉, 보쉬...
우리한테 거짓말 한거야
우릴 속인거라고
녹색은 괴물이 아냐 녹색은 인간이야
정확히 이게 없는..
무슨 소리하는거야?
아직 모르겠어?
피식별, 추적, 다 가짜라고
착각이고, 속임수야
그들한테 작전은 의미없어. 그냥 우리를 지켜보는거야
우리가 어떻게 하는지 그저 지켜보는거야
위기를 어떻게 극복하는지 보는거라고
알겠어? 우리가 어떤 훈련을 받았는지 생각해봐
괴물을 죽이기 위한 훈련!
아냐, 생존자들을 죽이라는 거야
생존자들을
그럼 바깥에 있는 놈들은 뭐야,
우리한테 총나발 지랄 한 놈들은 뭐냐고
인간이야
군대가 왜 인간을 죽이기를 바라겠어?
레즈닉, 보쉬.. 군대..
그들이 괴생명체야
걔들 생각에 우리는 애들이니까,
이런 추악한 일을 하는 데 잘 써먹을 수 있겠다 싶은거지.
우린 제5침공과 싸우고 있는게 아냐
우리가 제5침공이야
맙소사
그럼...
이제 어쩌지?
추적기 제거해
이건 탈영이야
돌이킬 수 없게 돼, 알고 있는거지?
너겟
기지에 남겨놓고 왔어
그게 안전할 거라고 생각했거든
이런
다시 가야겠어
죽으러 가는거야 그건
아니, 꼭 가야 돼
간다해도 신변이 보장 안돼
거기서 알아챌거야
거기다 그냥 둘 순 없어!
추적기 남겨 놓고 올거야, 찾아 오겠지
너네 먼저 가, 난 나중에 합류할께
덤보, 몸 어디에 총알이 박혀야 안죽지?
진심이야?
응 진심이야
몸 어디야? 진짜처럼 보여야 돼
산채로 들어갈 방법은 그것뿐이야
불가능해, 장기가 너무 많아
분명 있을거야
링어가 쏘면 돼, 잘 쏠거야
나보고 널 쏘라고?
갑자기 착한척 하지마
어디에 쏘면 돼?
어...
그게.. 어., 씌ㅂ.
푸~슝,
에반 워커
드론 감시를 피했더군
이봐요
총치우고, 그냥 가세요
캐시, 도망쳐!
내 총 어딨어
에반
총 버려
에반, 내려놔
캐시, 널 죽일려고 했으면
한참전에 이미 죽였을꺼야
정체가 뭐야
너도 그중 하나구나, 염병 괴물들.
난 사람이야
근데, 그것이기도 해
둘다야
그것들이 여기 온게 이번이 처음은 아냐
이전에도 왔었어, 그리고 나같은 감시자도 심어놨지
난 늘 이상한게 느껴져
시간이 지날수록, 어떤 목소리가 머리 속에서 떠나질 않아
아주 미약한 소리, 하지만 분명한 소리
그러다 그들 모함이 여기에 오면,
마치, 내가 무엇인지 번쩍 알게 돼
내가 무엇인지
사람을 얼마나 죽였어?
너네 가족도 죽였어?
아니
이건 질환...
그것들이 심은 질환,
니가 자처한 질환이겠지
너희 가족은, 널 아끼는 사람들이야
우리 종족은 그런 사랑을 그저 눈속임으로 간주해
본능이지
종족 보존을 위한 방어책
정말 그렇다고 믿어?
그랬지
근데 널 본 순간
모르겠어..뭔가
이해할 수가 없었어, 마치
너라는 존재가 날 다시 인간으로 돌리는 버튼 같다는 느낌,
다시 인간이 되고 싶다는 마음이 들게 했어
날 쏜게 너였어?
아니
난 널 살렸어
내가 틀렸어
그들도 틀렸어
사랑은 속임이 아니야, 실체야
이젠 알아, 니 덕분에 알게됐어
이봐, 물러서!
더 듣고 싶지 않아
그냥 거기 서있어
캐시 제발, 그냥 돕게 해줘
샘을 찾게끔 돕고 싶을 뿐이야
무릎 꿇어, 에반
빨리 무릎 꿇어
저기
군대도 그들이 조종하고 있어
아이들을 키우고 있지
뭣 땜에?
생존자들 죽일려고
그들이 널 쫓을거야
상대가 안될거야
따라오기만 해봐 너,
쏴버릴거야
대원들은 다 어딨어?
전사했습니다
군번이 뭔가?
둘-아홉-다섯!
둘-아홉-다섯. 살 수 있겠다
얼른 뜨자!
쓰리 탱고, 본부로 귀환한다
둘-아홉-다섯은 대원은 생존
나머지 대원은 전사했다
괜찮아요, 걱정마세요. 우리가 왔습니다
오-넷-칠
사망확인 안된 가족이 있나요
아뇨 저 혼자에요
일어서세요
왜 여기있는지 알고 있나요 캐시?
어..
복수를 위해서
그는 괴생물이네
알아
이걸로 보거라
그게 진짜 모습이지
숨은 얼굴이지
무슨 일이 있었나?
안좋았습니다. 써
우린 포위 당했고
숨을 곳을 찾아 뛰어다녔지만, 찾기가 무섭게..
사방에 적들이 있었습니다. 써
다 당했습니다
자네만 빼고
저도 총 맞았습니다. 써
그래도 살아있잖나
기적이지,
총알이 절묘하게도 치명적인 곳은
다 피해 맞았더구나
이렇게 해보자
자네가 거짓말을 그만두면, 나도 진실을 말하겠네
말해보게, 벤
뭘 알고 있나?
당신이 뭔지 알아요
날 죽일거죠? 안그런가요?
그래
왜죠?
대체 뭘 하고 있는거죠?
지금껏 우리는 뭘 하고..
필요한 영역을 확보한다는 것 외엔
달리 없어
우린 같은 존재야
아뇨
우린 종족 말살은 하지 않아요
물론 그렇겠지
줄곧 그렇게 해왔지
써, 레즈닉 원사가 죽었습니다
보안대에서 시체를 발견했습니다
어디야?
의무실입니다
그리고 더 있습니다.
서문 위병 세 명도 살해당했습니다
뭐야 이건 또?
폭발 같습니다, 본부 안에서 들리는 소리입니다.
저 친구 처리해
지원병들 본부 밖으로 빼야겠어
원더랜드행 비행기에 탑승시켜
수색대 투입시키고, 누구 짓인지 찾아내
남쪽 통로다!, 서둘러!
보안 카메라 전부 먹혔어
드론 불러들여, 그래야 뭐라도 볼 수 있지.
SOLDIER 3: Yeah, these are the changes from about 60 minutes ago.
? ?
Hey!
Don't move, all right! Don't move!
It's okay! Okay, all right!
Cassie? My name's Ben Parish. We used to go to high school together.
I know who you are.
What squad are you in?
I'm looking for my brother, Sam.
Sam?
Sam Sullivan? Sam Sullivan?
You know my brother?
Yes, yes, we're in the same squad.
You know where he is?
I'm trying to get to him right now.
SOLDIER: All recruits report to the transport area.
They're sending the kids off to war.
Vosch. The Army. They're Others.
Look, Sam is about to get on one of those planes.
If we don't go now, you're not gonna see him again. You understand?
We don't have much time.
All recruits report to the transport area.
All right.
Ready?
Come on.
Once the recruitsreach Wonderland,
get them ready for immediate deployment.
Yes, sir.
Transfer area's this way.
Hey!
This is a restricted area.
Hey, it's all right.
On your knees!
Hands behind your head!
No, it's fine. He's one of us. It's okay.
Evan, what are you doing here?
Helping you.
Who's he?
Ben Parish.
Ben Parish?
Yeah. Uh...
He was just here.
I told you not to follow me.
Well, I decided to ignore you.
I've been planting bombs.
In about 10 minutes, when the last plane full of kids takes off,
I'm taking this place down, for good.
I'm sorry I lied to you, Cassie.
I was wrong when I said I was both one of you and one of them.
You can't be both. You have to choose.
I choose you.
? ?
Go.
Get out of here.
I'll find you.
Who was that?
Evan Walker.
We gotta go find Sam.
I think Evan Walker's about to blow this place up.
? ?
Next floor up.
SOLDIER 4: Head tothe northeast corridor,number 22, now!
Which way?
This way.
SOLDIER: (OVER MICROPHONE) Stay with your group leader.
Proceed to the transport vehicles in a calm and orderly fashion.
Stay with your group leader.
Proceed to the transport vehicles.
SOLDIER 2: Come on. Move along, people.
Straight ahead.
Stay with your group leader.
Keep it moving.
Don't fall behind, everyone.
Where do they think they're going?
Once you are on the plane, you will receive further instructions.
Keep moving. Straight ahead.
Stay with your group leader.
What's her problem?
Sam! Sam!
Sam! Sam! Sam.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Hi.
Cassie!
Don't, don't.
We gotta go, all right?
Let's go.
Once you are on the plane, you will receive further instructions.
Come on.
Hi!
I missed you so much, Sam.
? ?
I missed you, Cassie.
Look what I brought back for you.
It's Bear.
I love you.
I love you, too, Sam.
Hey. Um...
I gotta take his tracker out.
All right? It's not gonna hurt, okay?
(EXPLOSION)
Is it back up?
All the recruits accounted for?
Yes, sir. Six barracks left.
Good.
Power up my bird. Last plane's in the air, evacuate the base.
Come on!
Shit! It's Vosch!
Run! Run! Go for the truck!
Go!
Sam, run faster!
Go! Go!
Come on, Sam!
Run!
Cassie!
Oh, shit!
Who is that?
Come on!
Come on! Get in!
Quick, Sammy. Get in!
All right, come on! Get in! Get in!
Drive!
Thanks for coming back.
(EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
? ?
DUMBO: Feel better?
ZOMBIE: Yeah, thanks, Dumbo.
Make sure you give her the food first.
DUMBO: Let me know if it starts hurting or anything like that.
Okay.
All right.
Teacup, how you feeling?
Pretty good.
RINGER: All right.
How much longer for food?
DUMBO: I don't know. Not long.
What are you looking at?
Trying to find the stars.
It's a little early, isn't it?
(CHUCKLES)
You were named after a star, right?
Cassiopeia.
Yeah. A cluster of stars.
I was named after Ben & Jerry's.
The truth. Yeah.
Nothing made my dad happier than ice cream.
I'm sure you made him happier.
Yeah.
So, uh...
What do we do now?
We have to save those other kids.
Yeah.
How are we gonna do that?
Dinner's ready.
I don't know yet.
Well...
Let's worry about that tomorrow
and just go get something to eat.
All right.
Hey, Sam.
Here, wake up, buddy.
Hey, there he is.
Come on.
Come on, lazy bones. Put your bear down, would you?
CASSIE: The Others see our hope as a weakness,
as a delusion.
But they're wrong.
It's our hope that lets us survive.
That lets us bend, but remain unbroken.
You two knew each other?
ZOMBIE: Yeah,we went to highschool together.
CASSIE: It's our hope that will let us win one day.
? ?
It's our hope that makes us human.
? I was born in a thunderstorm
? I grew up overnight
? I played alone I'm playing on my own
? I survived
? Hey, I wanted everything I never had
? Like the love that comes with light
? I wore envy and I hated that But I survived
? I had a one-way ticket to a place where all the demons go
? Where the wind don't change and nothing in the ground can ever grow
? No hope, just lies And you're taught to cry in your pillow
? But I'll survive
? I'm still breathing
? I'm still breathing I'm still breathing
? I'm alive
? I found solace in the strangest place
? Way in the back of my mind
? I saw my life in a stranger's face
? And it was mine
? I had a one-way ticket to a place where all the demons go
? Where the wind don't change and nothing in the ground can ever grow
? No hope, just lies And you're taught to cry in your pillow
? But I'll survive
? I'm still breathing I'm still breathing
? I'm alive
? You took it all, but I'm still breathing
? I had made every single mistake that you could ever possibly make
? I took and I took and I took what you gave, but you never noticed that I was in pain
? I knew what I wanted I went in and got it
? Did all the things that you said that I wouldn't
? I told you that I would never be forgotten And all in spite of you
? And I'm still breathing I'm still breathing
? I'm still breathing I'm still breathing
? I'm alive
? You took it all, but I'm still breathing
? I'm alive ?